The William Siegmann Collection, 1932-2007 IULC038 IULC038
Liberian Collections
- Research
  - Art (Box 10)
    - Review: "Radiance from the Waters: Ideals of Feminine Beauty in Mende Art", 1988 (Box 11)
    - "Ritual Masks"; Henry Pernet, 1992 (Box 11)
    - "Sacred Children: Twins in the Ritual and Art of the Yoruba of Nigeria"; Adams, Marie Jeanne (Monni), 1980 (Box 12)
    - "Sacred Forest" Film Transcript; Pierre Gaisseau, 1951 (Box 12)
    - "The Sacred Stool of Bachama"; Phillips Stevens, 1980 (Box 12)
    - "The Sculpture of Black Africa"; Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1971 (Box 12)
    - "Self Portraiture, Portraits, and Copywork Among the Mask Carvers of the Dan"; Eberhard Fischer, 1970 (Box 12)
    - "A Sense of Wonder: African Art from the Faletti Family Collection"; Mary Nooter Roberts & Alan F. Roberts, 1997 (Box 12)
    - "Shona Male & Female Artistry"; William J. Dewey, 1986 (Box 12)
    - "A Short History of the Bassa"; L. Baiogai Anthony, 1924 (Box 12)
    - "Sierraleonean Brass Masks"; W.A. Hart, 1980 (Box 12)
    - "Sierra Leone's Museum"; Easmon, 1961 (Box 12)
    - "Sierra Leone Museum, Freetown"; Janet L. Stone & H.U. Cole, 1965 (Box 12)
    - "The Simple Tools and Complex Designs of Kalabari Textile Artists"; Joanne Bubolz Eicher, 1981 (Box 12)
    - "Sphere's of Men's and Women's Creativity"; Monni Adams, 1980 (Box 12)
    - "Statistical Study of Mental Templates for Liberian Masks"; Laszlo Borsanyi, 1978 (Box 12)
    - "Strangers Among Us" Museum Pamphlet and News Articles; Smithsonian National Museum of African Art, 1982 (Box 12)
    - "A Structural Approach to Esthetics: Toward a Definition of Art in Anthropology"; Warren d'Azevedo, 1958 (Box 12)
    - "Structural Aspects of a Village Art"; Marie Jeanne (Monni) Adams, 1973 (Box 12)
    - "A Study of Face Masks from the Western Ivory Coast"; Marie-Noël Verger-Fevre, 1980 (Box 12)
    - "A Study of the Mask Complex of Northeast Liberia"; Carol M. Crawford Suchinsky, 1956 (Box 12)
    - "A Survey of Akan Arts and Crafts"; Martha Ehrlich, 1969 (Box 12)
    - "Survivors: Stone Carvings from Sierra Leone and Guinea"; Aldo Tagliaferri, 1978 (Box 12)
    - "Symbolism in the Art of the Yoruba Orisha"; Barbara Johnson, 1981 (Box 12)
    - "Three Art Styles of the Northern Congo"; Robert P. Boyce, 1969 (Box 12)
    - "To Dance the Spirit: Masks of Liberia" Summary Paper, undated (Box 12)
    - "Tondo Mask in the Pujehun Area of Sierra Leone"; Joseph Momoh, 1974 (Box 12)
    - "Traditional African Art"; Odita E. Okechukwu, 1971 (Box 12)
    - "Traditional Art of the African Nations in the Museum of Primitive Art"; Robert Goldwater (indroduction), 1961 (Box 12)
    - "Traditonal Art of West Africa: A Loan Exhibition"; SUNY Binghamton, 1972 (Box 12)
    - "Traditonal Bandi Weaving"; Judith Perani, 1976 (Box 12)
    - "Treasures of Ancient Nigeria"; Detroit Institute of Art, 1980 (Box 12)
    - "Twelve Workshop Styles in the Art of Sierra Leone"; Frederick Lamp, 1988 (Box 12)
    - "Twins in Upper Guinea"; H.U. Hall (Box 12)
    - "The Twins of Yorubaland"; Sirota Leon, 1967 (Box 12)
    - "Two Early Masks from the Dan Tribes in the British Museum"; William Fagg, 1955 (Box 12)
    - "Two Liberias at Mid Century: A Collector's View"; Carol Hotchkiss Malt, undated (Box 12)
    - "A Typology of African Masks"; Lou Ann Lambeth, 1969 (Box 12)
    - "Vegetable Ivory"; T.K. Penniman, 1952 (Box 12)
    - "The Victor K. Kiam Collection at the New Orleans Museum of Art"'; William A. Fagaly, undated (Box 12)
    - "Visual Art in Africa"; Frank Willett, undated (Box 12)
    - "The Visual Arts" From The African World: A Survey of Social Research; Roy Sieber, 1965 (Box 12)
    - "We Masks"; Pierre Harter, 1992 (Box 12)
    - "Western African Art and Artifacts"; Carol Hotchkiss Malt, undated (Box 12)
    - "The Western Guinea Coast"; Eberhard Fischer, 1981 (Box 12)
    - "Women's Art as Gender Strategy among the Wè of Canton Boo"; Monni Adams, 1986 (Box 12)
    - "Words and Things in a Crisis Among the Bo People of Western Cote d'Ivoire: The pwa Bowl"; Monni Adams, 2004 (Box 12)
    - "Yavi: A Mask From Liberia"; Dorith Ofri, 1973-1974 (Box 12)
      Original in French. Includes English translation.
    - Yoruba Christian Religious Art, undated (Box 12)
  - Colonization (Box 13)
    - "Abstract of a Journal" ( 1824 ); E. Bacon, undated (Box 13)
    - "Account fo the Native Africans of Sierra Leone" ( 1803 ), Thomas Winterbottom, undated (Box 13)
    - "Address Before the Pennsylvania Colonization Society" ( 1839 ); Ralph R. Gurley, undated (Box 13)
    - "Africa Redeemed, or the Means of Her Relief, Illustrated by the Growth and Prospects of Liberia" ( 1851 ), undated (Box 13)
    - "African Colonization - Its Progress and Prospects" ( 1863 ); William Allen, undated (Box 13)
    - "American Colonies in Liberia" ( 1839 ); Samuel Wilkeson, undated (Box 13)
    - Americo-Liberian Architecture; Susan Samuels, undated (Box 13)
    - "Benin to Bahia: Portuguese Empire in the South Atlantic" ( 1859 ); Phillip W. Porter, undated (Box 13)
    - "Colonization Journal" ( 1851 ), undated (Box 13)
    - "Day Dawn in Africa" ( 1853 ); Anna Scott, undated (Box 13)
    - "Developmental Nationalism & Lusotropicology"; Ronald H. Chilcote, 1966 (Box 13)
    - "English Acquisitions in Guinea and the East Indies" ( 1700 ); Nathaniel Crouch, undated (Box 13)
    - "The Europeans in Northen and Western Africa" ( 1799 ); John Leyden, undated (Box 13)
    - "From Colonization to Nationhood"; R. Fulton, 1969 (Box 13)
    - "George Schwab and the Peabody Museum Expedition to Liberia"; E.A. Hooten, 1929 (Box 13)
    - "History of the American Colony in Liberia From December 1821-1823 " ( 1829 ); J. Ashmun, undated (Box 13)
    - "Information About Going to Liberia: With Things Which Every Emigrant Ought to Know: Report of Messrs. Fuller and Janifer: Sketch of the History of Liberia: and the Constitution of the Republic of Liberia" ( 1852); American Colonization Society, undated (Box 13)
    - "Kru-Settler Relations in Sinoe County, Liberia, in the 1890s"; Mary Jo Sullivan, 1977 (Box 13)
    - "Liberia, Early History & Signal Preservation of the American Colony" ( 1833 ); William Innes, undated (Box 13)
    - "Louisiana State Colonization Society" ( 1853 ); Rev. William Anderson Scott (Box 13)
    - "Mandinka Adaptation to Colonial Rule in the Gambia"; Peter M. Weil, 1980 (Box 13)
    - Massachuetts Colonization Society Annual Report ( 1846 ), undated (Box 13)
    - Pennsylvania Colonization Society, First Annual Report ( 1827 ) (Box 13)
    - "Remarks on the Colonization of the Western Coast of Africa, by the Free Negroes of the United States, and the Consequent Civilization of Africa and Suppression of the Slave Trade" ( 1850), undated (Box 13)
    - Report of the Pennsylvania Colonization Society ( 1857 ), undated (Box 13)
    - "Scenes in the Interior of Liberia", Maryland Colonization Journal ( 1859 ), undated (Box 13)
    - "Settlers and Tribes: The Origins of the Liberian Dilemma"; W.W. Schmokel, 1968 (Box 13)
    - "Sketch of the Exploration and Settlement of the East Coast of Africa"; K.M. Kenyon, undated (Box 13)
    - "Some Notes Concerning the Barbadian Emigrants of 1865 "; Svend Holsoe, 1965 (Box 13)
    - "Study of Settler-Native Relations in Western Liberia 1821-1847 "; Svend Holsoe, 1969 (Box 13)
    - "Towards and Ethno-History of Liberia: The Early Colonization of the Dan"; Andreas Massing, 1988 (Box 13)
    - "Voluntary Colonists - Pagans" from The White Man's Grave ( 1836); F. Harrison Rankin, undated (Box 13)
  - Culture
    - "Achievement and Ascription in Liberia: A Comparative View"; H. Dieter Siebel, 1969 (Box 13)
    - "African Cultural Summaries"; George P. Murdock, 1958 (Box 13)
    - African Traditional Thought (Course Notes); Gay, John, undated (Box 13)
    - "Animism and Islam: A Mask from North-East Liberia"; Thomas K. Seligman, 1980 (Box 13)
    - "Art-ing, God-ing and Self-ing: Aspects of the Seamless Unity of African Traditional Culture"; J. Weldon Smith, undated (Box 13)
    - "Artistic and Sex Roles in a Limba Chiefdom"; Simon Ottenberg, 1983 (Box 13)
    - "Artistic Milieu For Men and Women in Western We (Guere) Villages"; Monni Adams, 1986 (Box 13)
    - "Arts and Societies on Guinee Forestiere"; Fred Lamp, 1991 (Box 13)
    - "Assongu: An Ivory Coast Terracotta Tradition"; Robert T. Soppelsa, 1981 (Box 13)
    - "Autonomous Judges: African Ordeals as Dramas of Power"; Elizabeth Tonkin, undated (Box 13)
    - "The Bassa Mask - A Stranger in the House"; Roger Dorinsville, 1973 (Box 13)
    - "The Birth and Development of Midwifery"; Ruth A. Etzel, 1976 (Box 13)
    - "Blue Goes Down: How Indigo Dye Came to Liberia"; Esther Warner Dendel, undated (Box 13)
    - "Body Ritual Among the Nacirema"; Horace Miner, 1956 (Box 13)
    - "Burial Sites in the Monrovia - Buchanan Area"; Cecily Delafield, 1969 (Box 13)
    - "Bushpigs, Anteaters and Automobiles: Aspects of Divination in Eastern Liberia"; Edward Lifschitz, 1987 (Box 13)
    - "Caribbean Public Celebrations in New York City: The Puerto Rican Parade and the West Indian Carnival"; Philip Kasintz & Judy Freidenberg-Herbstein, 1988 (Box 13)
    - "Carvers, Clients and Change in Western Liberia"; Thomas K. Seligman, 1981 (Box 13)
    - "Carving Up the Profits: Apprenticeship and Structural Flexibility in a Contemporary African Craft Market"; Harry R. Silver, 1981 (Box 13)
    - "Causality and Household Organization in Urban Africa"; W. Penn Handwerker, 1972 (Box 13)
    - "Changing Household Organization in the Origins of Market Places in Liberia"; W. Penn Handwerker, 1971 (Box 13)
    - "Complexities of Balance and Contrast in Kpelle Music"; Cynthia E. Schmidt, 1981 (Box 13)
    - "Cosmology and Symbolism on the Central Guinea"; M.C. Jedrej, 1986 (Box 13)
    - "The Country Cloth Culture in Sierra Leone"; C. Magbaily Fyle & Arthur Abraham, 1975 (Box 13)
    - "Country Medicine in a Transitional Culture"; John F.H. Stewart, 1964 (Box 13)
    - "Customary Rules of Governing Marriage and Domestic Relations Among Some of the Tribes of Liberia and West Africa"; Prilliamen, Jerry L., 1965 (Box 13)
    - "Dan and Mende Masks: A Structural Comparison"; M.C. Jedrej, 1980-1986 (Box 13)
    - "Dan Forest Spirits: Masks in Dan Villages"; Eberhard Fischer, undated (Box 13)
    - "A Description of the 1970 Grand Cess Gbo"; Thomas E. Hayden, 1972 (Box 13)
    - "The Developmental Function of Traditional Cooperative Societies in Africa"; H. Dieter Seibel, undated (Box 13)
    - "Diola Masking Traditions and the Cultural History of the Casamance; Peter Mark, 1981 (Box 13)
    - "Dumboy, the National Dish of Liberia" ( 1911); G.N. Collins, undated (Box 13)
    - "Ethnopsychiatry: An Afrosuriname Case Study on Paralysis and Voodoo Death"; Charles J. Wooding, 1981 (Box 13)
    - "Evidence in Nimba"; Peter Sevareid, 1993 (Box 13)
    - "Figurine Cults of the Southern Akan"; Timothy F. Garrard, 1981 (Box 13)
    - "Folktales, Proverbs, and Riddles From Gbundeland"; Nathaniel Kokolo Koikoi, 1975 (Box 13)
    - "Formal Public Titles for We/Guere Women, Cote d'Ivoire"; Monni Adams, 1991 (Box 13)
    - "Form and Meaning of Masks in Three Mende Societies"; William Louis Hommel, 1981 (Box 13)
    - "Forms of Divination Among the Wobe and the Guere of the Ivory Coast"; Alfred Havenstein,, undated, 1988 (Box 13)
    - "The Fulani Kerka: Islamic Symbol in Secular Context?"; Rachel Hoffman, undated (Box 13)
    - "The Funeral War Dance of the Grebo"; Isaac L. George, 1974 (Box 13)
    - Generalizations on African Traditional Thought, 1972 (Box 13)
    - "Harvet and Magic Among the Kissi"; Ralph Eberl-Elber, undated (Box 13)
    - "Heavenly Bodies: Menses, Moon, and Ristuals of License among the Temne of Sierra Leone"; Frederick Lamp, 1988 (Box 13)
    - History of Coffee, World and African Distribution, Production Practices, Markets, Etc., undated (Box 13)
    - "Initiation of Kru Chiefs - Grand Cess"; David Nah Wreh, 1975 (Box 13)
    - "Joy Manifest: Gho Masked Performance in Western Cote d'Ivoire"; Daniel Reed, 1994 (Box 14)
    - "Kalabari Men's Dress: A Sophisticated African Response to Culture Contact"; Tonye Victor Erekosima & Joanne Bubolz Eicher, 1981 (Box 14)
    - "Kinship Terminology and Social Organization of the Central West Atlantic Region"; Lucybeth Rampton, undated (Box 14)
    - Kissi Money, undated (Box 14)
    - "Kuba Embroidered Cloth"; Adams, Monni, 1979 (Box 14)
    - "The Land of the White Tiger" ( 1910); Edgar Allen Forbes, undated (Box 14)
    - "Liberia" ( 1906 ); Sir Harry Johnston, undated (Box 14)
    - "Liberian Cultural Patterns"; D.M. Foster, 1965 (Box 14)
    - Liberian Dress As Fashion Jane Martin, undated (Box 14)
    - The Liberian National Dance Troup from West Africa (The Dances and Their Meaning), undated (Box 14)
    - "The Liberian Rice Bag"; Esther Warner Dendel, 1974 (Box 14)
    - "Mancala, The National Game of Africa" (1896); Culin Stewart, undated (Box 14)
    - "Mandinka Fertility, Islam, and Integration in Plural Society"; Peter M. Weil, 1970 (Box 14)
    - "Mankind, Miracle Workers and the Divinity"; Dominique Zahan, undated (Box 14)
    - "Marriage Among the Kpelle" James L. Gibbs, 1963 (Box 14)
    - "The Masked Figure and Social Control: The Mandinka Case"; Peter M. Weil, 1971 (Box 14)
    - "Masked Spirit Impersonators"; Warren L. d'Azevedo, 1968 (Box 14)
    - "The Mask of Anarchy: The Destruction of Liberia and the Religious Dimension of an African Civil War"; Stephen Ellis, undated (Box 14)
    - "The Masking Tradition of the Central West African Area"; Judith Perani, undated (Box 14)
    - "Masks and Magic"; Olive L. Riley, 1955 (Box 14)
    - "Masks and Power"; Elizabeth Tonkin, 1979 (Box 14)
    - "Masks as Agents of Social Control"; Roy Sieber, 1962 (Box 14)
    - "The Masquerades of the Dan: An Introduction"; Eberhard Fischer & Hans Himmelheber, 1984 (Box 14)
    - Massalai, Momo Fina Drawings, undated (Box 14)
    - "Melegueta Pepper"; A.M. Van Harten, undated (Box 14)
    - "Men's Masking and Ritual in the 19th and 20th Century Adaptive Processes of the Mandinka of Senegambia"; Peter M. Weil, 1986 (Box 14)
    - Miscellaneous, 1973-1985 (Box 14)
    - Missionary Sketch Stories ( 1909 ); Alexander Priestly Camphor, undated (Box 14)
    - "Modeling Form in Mande Masking"; Peter M. Weil, 1988 (Box 14)
    - "The Musical and Social History of the Steel Band"; Hinderliter, Alison Ann, 1988 (Box 14)
    - "Music and Regionalism in Liberia: The Vai Song Repertoire as an Indicator of Ethnic Interaction"; Lester P. Monts, 1981 (Box 14)
    - "Music Clusteral Relationships in a Liberian-Sierra Leonean Region: A Preliminary Anaylsis"; Lester P. Monts, undated (Box 14)
    - Music of the Mende of Sierra Leone, 1965 (Box 14)
    - "Music of the Toma Guinea"; Simone Dreyfus, undated (Box 14)
    - "Native African Medicine"; George Way Harley, 1970 (Box 14)
    - Negro Culture in West Africa, undated (Box 14)
    - Nhaanmo Faces the Devil; Henrique Topka, undated (Box 14)
    - A Note on Cave Rock; Warren L. d'Azevedo, 1992 (Box 14)
    - The Nyabo Tale of Origin; Do Same Wallace, undated (Box 14)
    - "On the Interpretation of Intended Meaning in Kpelle Parables, Dilemma Tales and Adumbrated Accounts"; Beryl L. Bellman, 1976 (Box 14)
    - "The Organization and Functions of the Ragbenle Society of the Temne"; Vernon R. Dorjahn, undated (Box 14)
    - "The Politics of Cultural Despair: A Study in the Rise of Germanic Ideology"; Fritz Stern, 1961 (Box 14)
    - "Progress and Pageantry in Changing Nigeria"; W. Robert Moore, 1956 (Box 14)
    - "Purity and Pollution: Aspects of Freeton Masquerade Performance"; John Nunley, undated (Box 14)
    - "Questions of Identity at Mask Festivals Among the We (Guere) of Western Ivory Coast"; Monni Adams, 1990 (Box 14)
    - Raphia Looms Liberia, Jo Ellen Bower, 1974 (Box 14)
    - Recent Archaeological Investigation on the Liberian Coast: 1967-1969; Cecily Delafield, 1970 (Box 14)
    - Review: "Africa and Indonesia: The Evidenec of the Xylophone and Other Musical and Cultural Factors" ( 1964 ); J.D. Fage, 1965 (Box 14)
    - Review: "To Dance the Spirit: Masks of Liberia"; Ford Martin, 1989 (Box 14)
    - Rules for the Game Malan, undated (Box 14)
    - "The Rural Mind and Rural Society in the World of Tales"; Roger Dorsinville, 1968 (Box 14)
    - "Secret Medicines, Magic and Rites of the Kpelle Tribe in Liberia"; Wiliam E. Welmers, undated, 1949 (Box 14)
    - "Sierra Leone Country Cloths"; M.C.F Easmon, 1924 (Box 14)
    - "Social Change on the Kru Coast of Liberia"; Merran Fraenkel, 1966 (Box 14)
    - "Some Aspects of Household Organization Among Urban Bassa"; W. Penn Handwerker, undated (Box 14)
    - "Some Remarks on the Origin, Manners, Customs, and Superstitions of the Gallinas People in Sierra Leone" ( 1865 ); J. M. Harris, 1972 (Box 14)
    - Some Tribal Proverbs; Bureau of Folkways, 1969 (Box 14)
    - "The Specialist in Traditional Liberian Society"; Robert Luneberg, undated (Box 14)
    - "Spheres of Men's and Women's Creativity"; Marie Jeanne Adams, undated (Box 14)
    - Spirit Image and Identity; Leon Siroto, undated (Box 14)
    - "Study of a Culture With Its Masks and Functions"; Augustine Sandy, 1969 (Box 14)
    - Sucromo Village Culture; Akki Kulah, undated (Box 14)
    - "Taking the Mask by the Horns"; Peter Weil, 1987 (Box 14)
    - "Tattooing and Scarification in Sierra Leone and Liberia"; Marcilene Wittmer, 1970 (Box 14)
    - "Technology and Household Configuration in Urban Africa: The Bassa of Monrovia"; W. Penn Handwerker, 1973 (Box 14)
    - "Thinking With Animals"; Edward Lifschitz, 1982 (Box 14)
    - Thomas Seligman Interviews, 1980-1981 (Box 14)
    - "To Dance The Spirit: African Masks in Motion"; Christopher B. Steiner, undated (Box 14)
    - "Togba, a Women's Society in Liberia"; Etta Donner, 1938 (Box 14)
    - Traditional Cooperative Soceities in West Africa: A Systematic Analysis, undated (Box 14)
    - "Tribal Medicine in Liberia"; Richard M. Fox, 1971 (Box 14)
    - "The Tuntu Society of the Dema Chiefdom"; J. Hornell, 1929 (Box 14)
    - "The Use of Traidional Healers as the Community Health Workers Within the Village Setting"; Svend E. Holsoe, 1979 (Box 14)
    - "Village and Bush, Self and Other: An Ethnomusicological Dialogue with The Gho of the Cote d'Ivoire"; Daniel Reed, 1994-1995 (Box 14)
    - "Visual and Musical Dialectics of African Mbiras"; Cynthia Schmidt, undated (Box 14)
    - "Weaving in Bandiland", undated (Box 14)
    - "West African Masks and Cultural Systems"; Sidney L. Kasfir, 1988 (Box 14)
    - "What Liberians Call Themselves and Each Other"; Svend E. Holsoe, 1970 (Box 14)
    - "Women and Marriage in Kpelle Society"; Caroline H. Bledsoe, 1980 (Box 14)
    - "Women Excluded? Masking and Masquerading in West Africa"; Elizabeth Tonkin, 1983 (Box 14)
    - "World Ethnographic Sample"; George Peter Murdock, 1957 (Box 14)
  - Economics (Box 15)
    - "African Economies: Basic Characteristics and Prospects"; Frank R. La Macchia, 1964 (Box 15)
    - "Bureaucracy and Charisma in Ghana"; Lionel Tiger, undated (Box 15)
    - "Child Development and Economic Development in Liberia"; Gerald Erchak, 1979 (Box 15)
    - "The Development of the Liberian Coasting Trade: Commerce and Shipbuilding, 1822-1830"; Dwight Syfert, 1973 (Box 15)
    - "Dynamics of Urbanization in Africa"; Daniel F. McCall, 1964 (Box 15)
    - "Economic Activities in the Liberian Area: The Pre-European Period to 1820"; Svend E. Holsoe, 1076 (Box 15)
    - "Economic Activities in Pre-Liberian Societies"; Carl P. Burrows, 1986 (Box 15)
    - "Economic and Financial Aspects of the Lofa Project"; Annette Binnendijk, 1982 (Box 15)
    - "Economic Man in Africa"; Harold K. Schneider, 1972 (Box 15)
    - "A Economical Survey of the Western Province of Liberia"; Earl Parker Hanson, 1964 (Box 15)
    - "The Farm of the Guinea Trade" ( 1631 ); J. W. Blake, undated (Box 15)
    - "Gujarati Traders in East Africa in the Eighteenth Century"; Thomas Ricks, 1969 (Box 15)
    - "Houseing in Liberia"; U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development, 1970 (Box 15)
    - "Indigenous Capitalists and Entrepreneurs: The Role of the Mandinka in the Economic Development of Liberia 1870-1990 "; Augustine Konneh (Box 15)
    - "International Trade and Western Liberia"; Svend E. Holsoe, 1968 (Box 15)
    - "Investment Potential and Extended Family Groupings in an African Town"; Okon Ekenem & Edwin Charle, undated (Box 15)
    - "Iron Production and Iron Trade in Northern and Central Liberia"; Susan White, 1974 (Box 15)
    - "Kinship, Friendship, and Business Failure Among Market Sellers in Monrovia, Liberia, 1970"; W. Penn Handwerker (Box 15)
    - "Labor Migration and Rural Agriculture Among the Gbannah Mano of Liberia"; James Coleman Riddell, 1970 (Box 15)
    - "The Lebanese in Liberia: A Study of their Influence upon the Agricultural Marketing Process", undated (Box 15)
    - "The Liberian Charley: A Study in Third World Price Discrimination"; Fish, Carter & Robinson, 1978 (Box 15)
    - Liberian Coinage, undated (Box 15)
    - "Mano Labor Migration and Cash-Cropping"; James Coleman Riddell, 1969 (Box 15)
    - "Migrancy and Agriculture in Independent Malawi: A Case Study"; Ronald E. Gregson, 1970 (Box 15)
    - "Mobilizing Local Savings as a Source for Development Funda in Africa"; Thomas Hayden, 1972 (Box 15)
    - "Nitien: The Curious Case of Kru Money"; Scott Sheppard, 1971 (Box 15)
    - "The Origins of Privilige: Liberian Merchants 1822-1847 "; Dwight Syfert, 1975 (Box 15)
    - "The Origins of the Market System"; W. Penn Handwerker, 1970 (Box 15)
    - "Panta Chiefdom Development Programme" (Box 15)
    - "Population Distribution and Land Use" (thesis notes); Phillip Porter, undated (Box 15)
    - "The Present Setting for the Indigenous Economies of Sierra Leone and Liberia"; Vernon R. Dorjahn, undated (Box 15)
    - "The Problems of Social Accounting of Foreign Enterprise in Developing Nations"; Flumo Y. Stevens, 1980 (Box 15)
    - "Producing Rice in Liberia: The Farmer's Case", undated (Box 15)
    - "The Technology and Social Organization of Ariculture in a Loma Community, Lofa County, Liberia: A Research Proposal"; Jeanette E. Carter, 1973 (Box 15)
    - "Temne Beliefs and the Introduction of New Rice Varieties"; David P. Gamble, 1967 (Box 15)
    - "Trade and Travel" ( 1851 ); John Smith, undated (Box 15)
    - "Trade Interests of the Republic of Liberia"; John Olbrich, 1925 (Box 15)
    - "Traditional Farming in Liberia: A Preliminary Enquiry"; W.D. McCurtie, 1968 (Box 15)
    - "Traditonal Swamp Rice Cultivation in Upper Bong Country"; John Bowo Kellemu, 1967 (Box 15)
    - "Why the Kpelle Man Has Found it Difficult to Adapt Western Method of Swamp Rice Cultivation"; John Bowo Kellemu, 1967 (Box 15)
  - Education
    - African Studies Program Indiana University Newsletter, 1980 (Box 15)
    - "The 'Bush' School in Tribal Liberia"; Cecily Delafield, 1967 (Box 15)
    - "The Closing of the Kayeta Bush School as seen by Judy Gay", 1972 (Box 15)
    - Conference on the Learning Process in Village Schools - Cuttington College, 1966 (Box 15)
    - "Education and Mathematics among the Kpelle of Liberia"; John Gay, 1965 (Box 15)
    - "Education and Politics in Liberia and the United States: A Socio-Economic Comparison of Colony and Colonizer", 1976 (Box 15)
    - "The Educational and Employment Expectations of Liberian Secondary School Students"; Thomas Hayden, 1977 (Box 15)
    - "An Insight on Chedepo New Geeken Education ( 1963-1983 )" (Box 15)
    - Liberian Education Newsletter, 1982 (Box 15)
    - "Outlooks of African Students: A Survey of Cuttington College"; Richard M. Fulton, 1970 (Box 15)
    - "A Position Paper for a Community College System in Liberia", 1976 (Box 15)